And how to use norm -critical design -
–Can make visible invisible norms, habitual performances -
- And things that we take for granted in our everyday lives.
Norms that consciously or unconsciously can result in discrimination -
- And exclusion of different groups.
Together with a research group, we have together developed a method and approach.
-And it is first that we do a survey you can say -
- Above what it looks like within an organization.
For example, what norms prevent the development of equality and diversity in a workplace.
–And when we then compile and analyze what we have obtained through the mapping -
- So we not only present these research results -
- In the form of a scientific publication or report.
- The extent we translate these results into so -called norm -critical design concepts.
It is simply physical things that illustrate and visualize -
- The norms that we have seen as obstructs in the first step.
And this can be a bit provocative and that is the idea.
Because we want to visualize problems and obstacles -
- And so that the organization can jointly discuss "okay, this is what it looks like".
- There are a lot of studies that have pointed out that organizations like to - want -
“But it is difficult to work with their gender equality and diversity work.
And you have long -liked -
- Scientifically proven and concrete methods for this work.
And there has been something that I together with the research group I worked a lot with -
- Has sought to contribute.
To really develop methods that are perceived as meaningful -
- And which is actually a tool in the concrete change work.
- Many have lifted that you see a great value in working with -
- To visualize research results also in physical things.
And that is because theories -